意式焗饭还凑合 但
Risotto's not bad,but
和厨师声称的差得远了
it's not what chef said about the fortunato.
首先 他把迷迭香和番红花混一起
******
这算什么? 罐头装吗?
我的鱼还不差
My fish isn't bad.
但肯定也不好
But it's not great either,I'm sure.
警告过你别点鲷鱼的
I warned you against the snapper.
能平静下来吗?
Do you think it'll calm down?
天啊 我也希望
God,I hope so.
这人还真会自吹自擂 不是吗?
That guy is a bit of a blowhard,though,isn't he?
一点都不辣 根本吃不出辣味
The food's not spicy at all. You can barely taste it.
我的很辣
Mine's pretty spicy.
尝尝
Try it.
我没吃出来
I don't taste anything.
是你拿面包卷扔我的?
You been throwing rolls at me?
不是我
Um,it wasn't me.
真的 不是他
Really,he didn't.
很抱歉会有人那样做
I'm so sorry someone would choose to behave that way.
真的 我...
Really,i...
嗯
Yeah.
我...很抱歉!
I'm...So sorry!
真的 很抱歉 真的!
Really,really,really sorry!
不不 我发誓-- 不...是...我...
No,no,no,i swear,i-- It's...Not...Me.
血泪可能只是结膜下出血
Bloody tear could just mean subconjunctival hemorrhage.
感冒了喷嚏打得太厉害 导致味觉失灵
He sneezed too hard from a cold, which caused his lack of taste.
House不会接的
House isn't gonna care.
不强制戴黑领带意味着要戴黑领带吗?
Does black tie optional really mean black tie?
- 因为我不想去租-abc- 婚礼遇到点小障碍
'Cause I don't wanna rentabc- there's been a glitch with the wedding.
还有 House会对这个感兴趣的
And house will be interested.
小障碍?
A glitch?
病人切除了胼胝体以抑制癫痫
Patient had his corpus callosum cut to correct a seizure issue.
小障碍?
A glitch?
术后虽然癫痫止住了abc但他对分离的两脑适应不良
The seizures stopped after the surgery, But he's having trouble adjusting to a split brain.
小障碍?
A glitch?
这位是Taub医生
This is Dr. Taub.
告诉他买东西的事
Tell him about shopping.
我走进小卖部
Uh...I go into a grocery store.
一切都很正常
Everything seems normal.
走到收银处 却发现自己拿了些
I get to the checkout,And there's all
额外的东西 我不想拿的 我讨厌的东西
these extra items in my cart, stuff I didn't put there,stuff I hate.
我的左手讨厌我
My left hand hates me.
嗯 我想House会感兴趣的
Yeah.I think house'll be interested.
*咯吱咯吱 电车开来 *
* clang,clang,clang went the trolley *
* 叮叮当当 铃铛~*
* ding ding ding hmm hmm hmm *
只是警告你们-- 我心情很好
Just warning you-- i'm in a good mood.
而且腿不痛 所以我不知道接着会--
And largely pain-free,So I have no idea how things are going--
相异手综合征
alien hand syndrome.
是中风 还是在后院骑了小马?
Set off by a stroke,Or is there a pony in the backyard?
分裂脑
Split brain.
右脑控制左侧--
Right hemisphere controls the left and--
让生活痛苦
is making life miserable.
不按逻辑出牌的人常这样
Nonlogical thinkers often do.
这问题不是由分裂脑引起 手术已矫正了-
Current issue isn't the split brain. The surgery corrected--
你反对右脑?
you're dissing the right hemisphere?
做过手术的大部分人abc没感觉自己失去了什么
Most people who have this operation  don't even notice they're missing anything.
左脑控制语言 计算和逻辑
Left brain has language,arithmetic,rationality.
右脑是沉默的失败者
Right brain is a mute loser.
右脑更多受美学影响abc有更强的面部识别能力
Right brain is more aesthetically oriented, abcHas greater facial recognition.
没它我可做不了整形医生
I couldn't have been a plastic surgeon without it.
初中生活会变成什么样
Yes.And where would junior high be
要是我们不从审美角度评判人的长相
Without our ability to judge people on aesthetics?
右脑对时间和宇宙空间的感知更强
Right brain's also more aware of the present moment, Our place in the universe.
紧密联系爱与和平的纽带让人abc冲别人扔小面包
It's a universal daisy chain of peace  and love That throws buns at people.
他目前的症状可能由自身免疫病
His present symptoms could mean autoimmune disease,
鼻咽癌 感染或是感冒导致
Nasolacrimal tumor,an infection,or just a cold.
早上好 我的阳光
Good morning,sunshine.
我们有了新玩具
We got a brand-new toy.
想一起玩吗?
You wanna play?
我想和你谈谈
We need to talk.
真棒 我爱委婉说法
Great. I love euphemisms.
委婉是指你口是心非
By euphemism I mean when you say something, And it means something else.
开始排除诊断
Begin eliminating.
去查他家
Search the home.
这...
The,uh...
马才把脸放在你胸前一个半小时
Isn't that like locking the barn door After the horse
这会儿你就打算锁上马厩门了?
has put his face between your breasts For an hour and a half?
我是你上司
I'm your boss.
你是我手下
You're an employee.
我不常玩角色扮演 但要是你想...
Well,i'm not normally into role-playing, But if you wanna...
靠近你的人都会受伤 这是事实
People who get close to you get hurt.That's a fact.
你对医院来说很有价值 这也是事实
You're also a valued doctor in this hospital. That's another fact.
从现在起 我们只关注第二个事实
From now on,we're gonna focus on the second fact.
你不是为了昨晚的事来发飙的?
So this isn't you freaking out over last night.
这不是感情用事
This isn't an emotional decision.
我只是给你定下规则
I'm just giving you the rules.
你可以选择接受或离开
You can either accept them or leave.
我和Cuddy上床了
I slept with cuddy.
在她帮我戒断维柯丁后
After she helped me detox from vicodin.
我已经快24小时没吃了
I've been clean for almost 24 hours now.
好吧
Okay.
觉得我该告诉你声
Thought I'd mention it.
哇
Wow.
哇!
Wow!
两件事都要"哇"
One for each.
她是这么说的 哎...
That's what she said.Ha...
痛吗?
How's the pain?
她身上或许留下瘀伤...
She's probably got some bruising...
得 我晓得了 你是匹种马
Yeah,i get it.You're a stud.
这是件很了不起的事 House
This is serious,house.
我感觉比四小时前好多了
I feel better than I did four hours ago.
四小时后 会比现在更好
Four hours from now,i'll feel better than this.
来讲讲另一个"哇"
The other wow...
你和她当时都清醒?
You were sober.She was sober?
既清醒又明白且...性感
Clean and sober and hot.
喔!
Wow!
实在太棒了
This is fantastic.
你打算怎么毁掉这段关系?
How are you gonna screw it up?
本来有几个好方案
Several good options.
但不幸的是 她没打算给我这机会
Unfortunately,i don't think She's gonna give me the pleasure.
没等我醒来她就走了 而且5分钟前 abc她告诉我 我只是她的一名员工
She left before I woke up,and five minutes ago  She told me that i'm just an employee.
哈?
Ha.
没错
Yes.
那么说 要么她爱你所以患得患失
Well,either she's actually in love with you and scared,
要么她意识到昨晚的事abc是一个可怕的错误
Or she realized last night was a gigantic mistake...
你当时很无助很脆弱abc所以她母性大发...
You were needy and vulnerable,she was maternal...
你认为她和我做 是出于同情?
You think she jumped me out of pity?
不 我的意思是 无论如何你都得...
No.I'm saying whatever's going on,You...
和她好好谈谈
Need to talk to her.
那当然了
Absolutely.
病人有没有吓到你?
Does our patient freak you out a little?
没有
No.
如果他是两个人
If he's two people,
那么我们都是两个人abc只是我们不自知罢了
then we're all two people,And we just don't know it.
我们该认同哪一个身份?
What does that say about identity?
这只是...人类在自身发展中abc编出来的一套 完全不会困扰我
It says...We're making it up  as we go along,Which I find freeing.
自从搬出医学院的宿舍后abc我就没进过这么小的浴室
Wow,i haven't been in a bathroom this size  Since my dorm in med school.
那些是真菌吗?
Is that fungus?
是水蒸汽造成的
It's from the steam buildup.
Chase和Cameron的婚礼出问题了abc你有什么看法?
What do you think of this glitch  With chase and cameron's wedding?
两个人好端端的 又扯上了精子的事 abc怪可惜的
It's always a sad thing when sperm comes between people.
我听说今天的"精子"很不错
I hear the sperm is very good today.
我指三文鱼
I mean the salmon.
走开
Go away.
别桌满了
No other tables.
你让你老婆在冰箱里abc保存另一个男人冷冻的后代?
You'd let your wife keep another man's offspring On ice
以防万一吗?
next to the frozen peas just in case?
就是这么一回事
That's what this is about.
她还没准备好对我作出承诺
She's not ready to commit to me.
她作好了失败告终的打算
She's planning for failure.
你有没听说过abc雄性果蝇会在精液里释放毒素
Did you know that male fruit flies  have toxic chemicals in their seminal fluid
好杀死其它雄果蝇的精子?
That inhibit the sperm of other males?
Wilson说我们得谈谈
Wilson says we need to talk.
- 我们谈过了abc- 我也这么说
- We talked.  - I agree.
显然我们已经过了谈的阶段
This has clearly gotten past the talking stage.
搞什么?
What?
嘿 太好了
Hey.Great.
你找到我的MP3了吗?
Did you find my mp3?
没有
Uh,not yet.
但我带了你的刮胡套装
But I got your shaving stuff,
牙膏 除臭露 几本杂志...
Toothpaste,deodorant,some magazines...
还有你窗台上的仙人掌
And this cactus from your window.
你没必要这么做abc这些东西医院都有
You didn't have to do that,really. The hospital supplies all that stuff.
为了让另一半的你也喜欢我
I'm still trying too hard,huh?
我未免太煞费心思了 对吧?
Trying to get your other half to like me.
别这么说 好吗?
Don't say that,okay?
我喜欢你
I like you.
也就是说-- 你别想太多
Which means that-- We shouldn't read into that.
抗真菌药物
Anti-fungal meds.
通常我们会用静脉注射
Ordinarily,we'd put them in your iv,
但看来你的右脑不大喜欢打点滴...
But since your right brain doesn't seem too fond of ivs...
过几天你就会好起来了
You should be feeling better in a few days.
我得回去上班了
I have to get back to work.
Rick说你的工作还等着你回去干呢
Rick says your shift will be waiting for you  When you get back.
谢谢
Thanks.
噢 天啊!
Oh,my god!
天啊! 对不起
God!I'm sorry.
非常 非常抱歉
I'm so,so sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我得-- 我得回去上班了
I have to-- I have to get back to work.
宝贝 别走! 那不是我!
Babe,wait,hold on!No,it wasn't me!
我不能走路了
I can't walk.
显然不是真菌导致的
Well,obviously,it wasn't the fungus.
也不是协调性的问题
And it's not a coordination issues.
脱水会使身体失去平衡abc我们还没给他打过点滴
Dehydration can cause loss of balance. We haven't had him on iv.
不 皮肤张力很好
No,good skin turgor.
不是直立性低血压
Not orthostatic.
说不定我们缴的税派上用场了
Could be our tax dollars at work.
造出了新的公路和桥梁
Constantly building new roadways and bridges.
脑膜瘤 慢性生长
A meningioma.Slow growing.
可能会扩散到颅腔的软骨后abc被颅骨隐藏起来
Could extend along the subosteal layer Of  the cranial cavity and be hidden by the bone.
癌细胞会在左右脑之间重新搭起通路
The cancer cells are actually re-growing  a connection Between the left and right hemispheres.
如果你是对的 两半大脑会再度对话
If you're right,the two halves have begun Sending messages again,
但在现阶段 他还无法感知 但是...
but it's too early In the process for him to pick up on it But...
我们可以做个测试
We can test for it.
证据在此
Proof.
你没找她谈 对吧?
You didn't talk to her,did you?
如果找她谈 她会说谎 我也会说谎
If I talked,she'd have lied,i'd have lied.
虽说负负可以得正
And though two negatives make a positive,
但我想 拍张热成像照片来得更直接
I thought thermal imaging photos seemed simpler.
和我呆了不到一分钟后abc她的发热区骤然增加
Note how many more heated areas appear  After less than a minute with me.
这可能是出于爱 也有可能是愤怒
So it's either love or possibly rage.
你别找她谈
Don't talk to her.
我没打算找她谈
I he no plans to talk to her.
掺和别人的事是你的天性
Manipulation is in your genetic code.
你认为我做错了abc所以要把它往正路上掰
You think i'm making a mistake,you move in to correct.
你这么做的确错了
You are making a mistake.
她撒谎了
She lied to me.
要么是昨晚 要么是今天
Either last night or today.
我得搞清楚是哪次 还有为什么
I need to find out which and why.
显然热成像是最佳办法
And clearly,thermal imaging is the way.
这不是一个病例
This isn't a case.
你也不是要找诊治方案
You're not looking for a diagnosis.
如果你重视这段关系
If this matters at all to you,
拜托 哪怕仅此一次 abc用成年人的方式处理
Please,for once in your life,be an adult.
眼睛紧盯着加号
Keep your eyes focused on the plus sign.
在你右侧出现的符号abc只有你的右脑能看见
Any image that appears on your far right  Will only be seen by your left brain.
在左侧出现的符号abc也只有左脑能看见
And any image on your far left  Will only be seen by your right brain.
好的
Okay.
我们从报单词开始
Just start by saying the words.
书本
Book.
长颈鹿
Giraffe.
柳树
Willow.
幸运的
Fortunate.
你没有念出那个单词
You're not saying the word.
我没看到单词
I didn't see a word.
你能不能画出这个单词所代表的物体?
Could you draw a picture Of  what you think the word might be?
我没有看到...
Uh,look,i-i didn't see...
蜡烛
Candle.
实在太酷了
This is so cool.
没错 一点也不可怕
Yeah,that's not freaky at all.
没有交流
No communication.
目前为止
So far.
Scott 你为什么要站起来?
Scott,why are you standing?
我觉得有点冷
I'm a little chilly.
我想回房拿件毛衣 可以吗?
I thought i'd get a sweater or something from my room.Is that okay?
再等一会儿
A few more minutes.
看好了 女士们先生们 abc这就是左脑的作用...
And that,ladies and gentlemen,Is the left hemisphere...
孜孜以求地寻找答案
The side that's obsessed with finding answers,
追求凡事的合理化abc负责解释一切
The one that needs things to make sense,the interpreter.
告诉我们 我们是谁abc以及我们在干什么
That's where we tell the story Of who we are and why we do things.
但出错的也是它
That's also the side that was wrong.
右脑的优势在于不循逻辑思考
Right brain's advantage is that it isn't logical,
不是从个别细节中得出结论
Doesn't choose which details to look at,
而是找出隐含的联系
Makes connections you could never see.
你低估了"沉默的失败者"的作用
You owe your insight to the "mute loser.
那我送它一张费城球票作为补偿好了
" i'll send it tickets to a phillies game.
虚构症状说明左右脑没有交流abc也就是说 你的猜测是错误的
Confabulation means no communication.Means your theory's wrong.
但他的确觉得冷
But he is cold.
你为什么要挠?
Why are you scratching?
很痒
It itches.
呼气有氨味
Ammonia breath.
你的肝正在衰竭
Your liver is failing.
得让他们看统计数字abc才会批这个价格
I know for them to approve this price, They'll need statistical documentation.
怎么了?
What?
干嘛盯着我看?
Why are you looking at me?
你一进门我就看出来了 你想说的...
When you first walked in,I was under the impression you wanted to...
是别的事情
Say something else.
没
Nope.
关于House和我
About house and me.
没什么好谈的
There's nothing to talk about.
我要求做个肝脏活检
I want permission to do a liver biopsy.
怀疑是结节病
We're looking for sarcoidosis.
好
Fine.
什么叫"好"?
What do you mean,fine?
你说什么叫"好"?
What do you mean what do I mean?
你是说 因为肝脏活检
Do you mean because a liver biopsy Is not a test that
无论怎么想 都不算危险的检查
by any stretch of the imagination, Can be considered risky,
所以要求我批准实际是浪费我时间
So asking my permission is essentially wasting my time,
而你想看看我如何反应?
And you're wondering what my reaction to that will be?
是
Yes.
你是想惹我生气?
Are you trying to make me angry?
是
Yes.
做你的活检去 还有门诊工作
Do your biopsy.And also do your clinic hours.
我不做门诊
I'm blowing off my clinic hours.
是么? 那我们走着瞧
Really?Let's see how that goes.
还是没生气
Still not angry.
一会再试试
Try again later.
抱歉 我知道我有点体臭
Sorry.I know i'm a little ripe.
经常出汗
Just a sweaty guy.
- 最近?abc- 一直
Recently? - Always.
嗯 还有只不听使唤的左手
Uh,with a crazy left hand.
有时我幻想着砍掉它
Sometimes I fantasize about cutting it off.
幻想而已
Just a fantasy.
手疯了 我还没
It's the hand that's crazy,not me.
干吗?
What?
它连超声棒都打 对针头会什么反应?
If it doesn't like an ultrasound wand, How's it gonna react to a needle?
能在这屋里放音乐不?
Can you get music into this room?
我觉得你是利用跟Cuddy的关系abc来替代药物了
I think you're using your relationship  with cuddy As a replacement for drugs.
戒毒本该让你迅速进入强烈痛苦中
You should be in more pain so soon into detoxing,
但你的体内却充满了浪漫内啡肽
But your body's full of romantic endorphins.
最重要的是abc你还用寻找证据来分散注意力
And on top of that,You create this distraction of looking for proof.
你觉得我该停手 好让痛苦涌现?
Think I should stop and let the pain flood back?
Cuddy不是维柯丁替代品
Cuddy is not a vicodin substitute.
恰恰相反
Quite the opposite.
你必须等她准备好
You have to wait for her to be ready.
建议不错
Great advice.
当作我听从好了
You pretend that i'm gonna do that.
你已经做了两个重大的人生改变
You've made two major changes in your life.
这时候任何人都做不了最佳抉择
Not a time anyone's judgment is at its best.
你以前不是常说abc我不吃药 判断力会更好吗?
Didn't you use to argue That my judgment would be better off drugs?
承认吧 -- 你好奇我干嘛非惹她生气
Admit it--you're curious why I wanna make her angry.
我肯定原因很纠结 错误 还愚蠢
I'm sure it's convoluted,wrong,and stupid.
你特想知道我在她咖啡杯里abc发现了什么吧
You're dying to know what I found on her coffee cup.
才不
No.
- 因为 --abc- 催产素
Because-- oxytocin.
催产素...
Oxytocin...
一种与情感联结有关的化学物质?
The chemical involved in emotional bonding?
她嘴上说不...
Her lips say no...
荷尔蒙却大喊"哦也 再来!"
Her hormones say,"oh,my god,yes,more!
不对 要确定她指数上升
" no.For you to know her levels were elevated
你必须知道她正常状况数值 作对比
You'd need a base line to compare them with.
我付钱让健身房的一家伙abc从垃圾桶里取回了一个她喝过的水瓶
I paid the guy in the gym To retrieve  one of her water bottles from the trash.
爱让人无所不能
Love inspires us to greatness.
所以我要让她情绪失控...
So I need to make her lose her temper...
好破碎她的错觉 向我和她证明
Which breaks her delusion,Which demonstrates to me and to her
外表之下暗生情愫
That there is something underneath this facade.
然后呢? 她承认一切 投入你怀抱?
And then what happens?She admits everything and falls into your arms?
这是可能性一 可能性二...
That's outcome one.Outcome two...
是她杀了我
Is she kills me.
我看眼下是对半的可能
I think it's 50/50 right now.
很好
Great.
我知道你会这么说!
I thought you'd say that!
你肯将自己承诺给 -- 一个人
You're committing yourself to something-- someone.
虽说 方式幼稚 但毕竟是好事
I mean,it's childish in a way,But ultimately great.
假设...
Assuming...
你真的希望自己成功?
Are you absolutely sure you want this to succeed?
为什么有一老头站我门口?
Why is an old guy standing in my doorway?
Eugene Schwartz
Eugene schwartz.
Cuddy医生让我到这看门诊
Dr. Cuddy asked me to come up here from the clinic.
她说你在办公室接待门诊
She says you're seeing patients in your office.
这样还是免费的吧?
It's still free,though,isn't it?
她让他到这来
She sent him.
其中肯定有奥妙
That's gotta mean something.
我去找我的解谜魔戒
I'll go get my decoder ring.
我咯咯叫
I squawk.
像只鹦鹉
Like a parrot.
不对 不是这样
No,that's not it.
几个月前开始的
It started a few months ago.
我在车库里做木匠活
I was doing some woodworking in my garage.
试着做把椅子
I was trying to make a chair.
是椅子还是?
Was it the chair?
不管了 反正就是突然间
Anyway,all of a sudden,from nowhere,
这个奇怪的嗓音从我口中爆出 -- 嗑!
This strange noise comes bursting out of my mouth-- Caaaww!
很难模拟
Tough to fake that.
裤子不错
Nice pants.
我老伴Mona说 我快把她骨头震断了
My wife mona thinks i'm bustin' her chops.
严重影响我婚姻
It's ruining my marriage.
我们去哪?
Where are we going?
你左手更愿意对空弹吉他abc而非阻挠我检查?
So your left hand would rather play air guitar Than give me a hard time?
它对空气吉他的欲望胜过abc系鞋带 拿刀叉...
It'd rather play air guitar than tie shoes,eat dinner...
你右手也在弹
Your right hand's playing too.
我不想打击左手
I don't wanna discourage it.
他指甲下有裂痕出血
splinter hemorrhages under his fingernails.
那是什么? 那--
What's that?What--
血压 血氧 在下降!
bp and 02 sats are dropping!
一袋B型阴性血!
Need a bag of b-negative in here!
不是结节病
So much for sarcoidosis.
指向凝血问题
Points to a clotting issue.
凝血可以解释所有症状abc为什么我们不在办公室谈?
Clots would explain all his symptoms.  Why aren't we in the office?
我受够了门诊工作
I'm tired of clinic duty.
只有一种情况会导致咯咯叫 对吧?
There's only one thing that could cause squawking,right?
恩
Yeah.
给病人注入了肝素 做了心脏回声测试abc看是否有血块 但--
We gave him heparin and did an echo of his heart  To see if it was throwing clots,but--
- 心脏也在弹吉他?abc- 心脏没有问题
more air guitar? - The heart's fine.
我们还想检测abcV莱顿凝血因子 C蛋白 S蛋白
We wanted to test for factor v leiden,Protein c,protein s,
但他手玩累了 不肯配合了
But the hand got tired of cooperating.
只得把他麻醉了
We finally knocked him out.
反正所有检测结果都是阴性
And all those tests came up negative anyway,
不然你们早兴高采烈告诉我abc你们的高明诊断了
Or you would have opened by telling me Your brilliant diagnosis.
他为出汗道歉 说是一直有这毛病
He apologized for being sweaty,Said it had always been an issue,
如果这是症状呢?
But what if it's a symptom?
有些癌症会导致夜里盗汗 引发凝血abc如淋巴瘤...
There are cancers that cause night sweats  And can lead to clots-- lymphoma...
或者胰腺癌
Or pancreatic cancer.
给他的胰腺摄片
Go scan his pancreas.
还有...
And...
试试放Led Zeppelin乐队的歌
Try led zeppelin.
我们一直感恩医院abc在Leo盲肠炎发作时所作的努力
We've always remembered what this hospital  did for leo When his appendix burst.
但这么大金额的支票...
Still,a check this size...
抱歉打扰下
Sorry to interrupt.
这是我的便便
Here's my poo.
House医生要我尽快拿来给你
Dr. House said to bring it over and  leave it with you As soon as I could.
我不知道你们是否有专业叫法--
I don't know if you people have an official term for it--
粪便样本
stool sample.
啊 对
Ah,yes.
谢谢 我会处理的
Thank you.I'll take care of it.
这东西还真不是说有就有的
It's hard to rush these things.
即便吃了一堆花椰菜
Even if you've eaten a lot of broccoli.
你要去哪?
Where you goin'?
Annie来电
Annie called.
她不会来了
She's not coming back.
这不是离开的好时机
This is not the best time.
你说过肝素可以防止新血块形成
You said the heparin would keep new clots from forming.
也许 但显然还有东西在引发凝血
Maybe.But something's obviously causing the clots.
- 如果你患了胰腺癌--abc- 我们不是想吓到你
- If you have pancreatic cancer- - we're not trying to scare you,
但即使是癌症早期 死亡率--
But even in its early stages,the fatality rate--
- 如果你离开--abc- 闭嘴!
- you walk out of here- - stop!
听着 我希望你们设身处地为我考虑
Look,i'd ask you to put yourself in my place,
但没人能体会我的感受
But nobody can put themselves in my place.
是她爱上别人了?
Did she find somebody new?
是我关心不够? 都不是
Was I not being attentive enough?No.
她只是受够了被一只手侮辱
She's just tired of being insulted by a limb.
她说我对她的感情是混杂的
She said that my feelings toward her were mixed.
我的感情才不混杂
Well,my feelings aren't mixed.
你没要离开 除非你是想裸奔
You're not goin' anywhere Unless you wanna go naked.
你的右脑知道该留下
Your right brain knows you need to stay.
我的右脑是混球
My right brain's an ass.
有空没?
Got a minute?
这杯子有点诡异
There's something wrong with this cup.
我需要找个人帮我思考这问题
I need someone to bounce ideas off of,
就像你用白板一样abc这方法可是你教我的
Someone to be my whiteboard.That's how you taught me to work.
我眼下有三种选择
I have three choices:
一 我可以面对分手的事实
first--i can accept it's over,
假装我们没在同一所医院共事
Pretend we don't work in the same hospital,
在走廊擦肩而过的时候abc就选择性失明 假装没看见
Have selective visual impairment When we pass each other in the hall.
二 我接受分手的事实abc然后收拾东西走人
Second--i can accept it's over and leave--
你不然试试惹他发火呗
or you could try making him angry.
绝佳的第三选择
Standard choice number three.
三...
Third...
我可以跟他谈谈abc但说实话我也没啥更多好说的了
I can talk to him,But it's not like I have any new facts I can present.
Chase的浪漫爱情观abc现实根本无法与之抗衡
And chase has this romantic view of love That reality can't compete with.
- 我知道你怎么做才行abc- 怎么做?
- I know how you could succeed. - How?
一句简单的咒语搞定
Just say the magic words--
"我会杀光前老公的精子"
"i will destroy my husband's sperm."
哦 你是说不放弃精子为前提
Oh,you mean succeed without doing that.
大概不会
Probably not.
我有顾虑 这很正常
I have doubts. Normal doubts.
没人希望坏事发生abc但有所准备也无妨啊
It's not wrong to prepare for bad things to happen Even if you don't expect them to.
谁也不想房子失火abc但我还是会买火灾保险
I don't expect my condo to burn down,But I have fire insurance.
病人的女朋友抛弃了他abc于是他不想在这治病了
Patient's girlfriend left him. Now he wants to leave us.
如果你的房子买不了火灾险abc你会睡大街吗?
If your condo rules don't let you buy insurance,Would you go homeless?
他的病房在那边
His room is this way.
怎么 你觉得我有招?
What,do you think I can fix this?
我们得给他一些abc只有留在医院才能得到的好处
We need to offer this guy something he can only get If he stays in the hospital--
感情顾问
relationship counseling.
- 我不知道他女朋友还...abc- 我是指他两个脑半球之间的感情
- I don't know if his girlfriend's-- - I mean his two hemispheres.
那可是一切感情的源动力abc不可或缺的重中之重啊
That's the breakfast of relationships-- The most important one of the day.
你得帮忙露一手了
We need your special skills.
那人在么?
Is the guy out there?
那个能治好我右脑的人在么?
The guy that's gonna make my right brain work?
有没搞错...
Oh,for...
你觉着你的右脑想要什么?
What do you think your right brain wants?
我怎么知道? 它疯疯癫癫的
How should I know? It's crazy.
它尽做那些我从来不做的事
It does things I would never do.
维尔松管略微扩张 但仍属正常
Duct of wirsung's slightly enlarged But within normal parameters.
说话啊
Say something.
它不会说话 没法主动跟你交流
It's mute. It can't communicate with you.
也许你该主动跟它交流看看
Maybe you should try communicating with it.
"跟她聊聊"
"talk to her."
这也没啥难的嘛 是吧?
the well isn't deep,is it?
主宰权在你这边 一切决定都在于你
You're the dominant half. You make all the decisions.
右边的没有任何控制权
The right side has no control over anything.
应该挺沮丧的哈
It must be... Frustrating.
未发现任何集聚
No masses in body or tail segments.
我无法与它交流 这就是问题...
I can't communicate with it.That's the whole--
当你决定去杂货店时 你怎么做?
when you decide to go and get groceries,what do you do?
什么意思? 我就穿好衣服去呗
What do you mean?I put on my jacket,and I go to the store.
你的右脑可不明白abc你为啥忽然要起来穿好衣服
Your right brain has no idea Why you're suddenly getting up and putting on your jacket.
它只是一起被拽过去的
It just gets dragged along.
下次的话 先大声说出来
Next time,try saying it out loud.
就冲着空气说?
Just say to the empty air,
"嘿 花生酱没了 咱去杂货店吧" 这样?
"hey,i think i'll go to the store Because we're out of peanut butter"?
人家培养你们当咨询师的时候abc你们究竟学到了点啥?
How much did they teach you about people like me When you were learning to be a therapist?
我是肿瘤专家
I'm an oncologist.
右脑貌似挺喜欢他顶嘴的abc完全没有动静
The right brain likes what he's saying. Hasn't moved the entire scan.
但我们目前毫无进展
Hasn't gotten us anything,though.
扫描很正常 不是胰腺癌
Scan's clean. It's not pancreatic cancer.
在形成肿瘤之前 凝血也可能是问题所在
Clotting could be a problem well before a solid tumor forms.
病根很可能还是胰腺
It can still be pancreatic.
话是没错 但要是想找到证据支持
Yes,but if you want a diagnosis Backed by actual evidence,
我们恐怕还得看看别的部位
We should probably look at other cancers.
- 我是Houseabc- 我又咯咯叫了!
- House. - I just squawked!
- 啥?abc- 我是Eugene Schwartz啊
- What? - Eugene schwartz,
你昨天给我看过病的 我刚刚又咯咯叫了!
your patient from yesterday.I just squawked!
我本来在给Mona买花abc付钱给小贩的时候就又来了!
I was buying some flowers for mona. It happened when I was paying the clerk!
- 我敢说这号码是Cuddy医生给你的abc- 是啊!
- I assume dr. Cuddy gave you this number. - Yes!
她跟我说 一咯咯叫就打这个电话
She told me to call you any time I squawked
- 白天晚上都行!abc- 很抱歉 但是...
- Day or night! - I'm sorry,but
我可能要没信号了abc因为我正要开进山谷隧道呢
i'm about to lose you Because i'm about to drive into a tunnel In a canyon
在飞机上 所以我要挂了
on an airplane while hanging up the phone.
可能会有更多电话打进来abc咱们得迅速
I might be getting some more phone calls,So let's make it fast.
- 可能是淋巴瘤abc- 我再说一遍 是胰腺的问题
- Lymphoma-- - that's right,pancreatic.
我知道是胰腺的问题 我敢肯定有证据abc我们肯定都看过了 我只是没法...
I know it's pancreatic.I know there's evidence.I know we've seen it.I just can't--
左右脑沟通不畅?
right brain,left brain issues?
要是癌瘤太小了 找不着abc那就复杂问题简单化
If the cancer's too small to find,Let's make it easier.
给他开刀 给肿瘤染色
Let's open him up and paint it.
有一种使用蝎毒素和红外线涂料的新方法
There's a new procedure using scorpion toxin And infrared paint.
只有癌细胞会被染色 很容易辨认出来
Paint only works on the cancer cells,Makes 'em easier to spot.
单纯刺激胰腺都会造成凝血
Just agitating the pancreas can cause clotting,
你还想用这方法治疗abc已经有胰腺凝血病症的病人?
And you wanna do it to a guy whose problem is clotting.
要是胰腺癌的猜想是正确的
If i'm right about pancreatic cancer,
他要活下来的唯一希望abc就是找到癌细胞并将其移除
The only chance he's got Is finding and removing those cancer cells now.
他脑部的核磁共振显示abc他颈部向上的血管十分狭窄
His brain mri showed narrowing in the blood vessels Leading up from the neck.
要是真出点什么差错 他可能会没命
If we do shake something loose,we could kill him.
或他局部"没命"
Or one of him.
脑部血凝会梗死其中一个半球abc对另一个毫无影响
Clot in his brain could kill one of them Without affecting the other.
他说不定会同意呢
He might actually be okay with that.
- 这得要多久?abc- 如无意外...
- How long's it gonna take? - Assuming he doesn't crash...
几分钟吧
A few minutes.
嘿...
Hey...
你和Cameron之间的事
You and cameron.
我感到很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
我不想睡大街
I don't wanna be homeless.
行 那公寓给你住 我再重新找...
Okay.You can stay in the condo.I'll find some other--
我不是这意思
that's not what I mean.
我想嫁给你
I wanna marry you.
我领了销毁精子的申请表
I got the forms to destroy the sperm.
- 你确定?abc- 确定
- You sure? - Yeah.
我很想拥抱你 但那样我就得重新消毒了
I wanna hug you,but then i'd have to rescrub.
我明白
I know.
血压下降
Bp's dropping.
快去吧
Go.
没有癌症迹象
No sign of cancer.
高压90 低压60
Bp's 90 over 60.
你还没回答我的问题
You never answered my question.
放宽心
Relax.
咱俩的友谊没有灭亡
Our friendship is not doomed.
感谢上帝啊 但我的问题是
Thank god.But my question was
你是真心喜欢Cuddyabc还是仅仅把这当成另一个挑战?
do you really want cuddy,Or is this just another challenge?
你是担心我一旦交了女朋友
You're worried that once i'm in a relationship
咱俩的传奇就会终结吧
You and me'll be over.
嘿! 我可强烈支持你交女朋友啊abc我觉得这是件好事
Hey!I'm actually for this. I think this is great.
但若你动了真心 又不愿认真对待的话
But if you're serious and you don't treat it seriously,
你就会受伤的
Then you will get hurt.
你要是不肯承认这一点
And if you don't accept that,
那就承认她会因此受伤
Then accept that she will get hurt.
她看上去生气么?
She look angry?
要是她抬头看到你在这的话...
If you're standing there when she looks up here--
哦 大事不妙
oh,no.
脉动80
Systolic's 80.
得先把这缝合了才行
Gotta finish this suture before I can get out.
给他注射多巴胺
Give him a dopamine drip.
我们看的时机不对
We weren't looking up at the right time.
赶紧说重点行不 我们正忙呢
Get to your point. We're a little busy here.
不是癌症导致的凝血
The clots aren't from cancer.
- 心脏才是源头abc- 做过心脏超声波了 没有血块
- They're coming from his heart. - We echoed the heart.No clots.
我们看的时候确实没有abc我开头说的不就是这意思么?
Not while we were looking. Didn't I open with that?
- 是心律失常 才导致了凝血abc- 没有心律失常
- The clots were caused by an arrhythmia. - No arrhythmia.
是我们看的时候没有!
Not while we were looking!
间歇性心律失常
Intermittent arrhythmia.
这家伙一受点刺激就乱拔针管
This guy pulls our equipment off at the slightest provocation.
要看到心律失常 就得一直盯着他
We'd have to be watching at the exact moment it happened,
要我说 你俩就甭瞎捣鼓了 就现在吧!
Which i'm guessing,Given the way you two are scrambling around like idiots,Is right now!
没错 做个经食管超声心动图
Yes,i'm saying do a transesophageal echo.
- 得赶紧让他心率恢复正常abc- 是啊 做完心动图再说吧!
- We have to get his bp stable. - Absolutely.Right after the echo.
脉速70
Systolic 70.
上回超声波的时候 他心脏还倍儿棒呢
The heart looked healthy at the last echo.
心律失常也不会导致正常心室出现凝血
And an arrhythmia wouldn't cause clots in a healthy ventricle.
从左心耳查起吧
So start with the left atrial appendage.
- 喔abc- 没错
- Wow. - Yep.
我真的好无敌
I did it again.
控制住这可怜虫的血压 把左心耳封住
Now get this poor guy's bp under control And seal off the appendage.
现在要做的
Then all we have to do
就是找出破坏心脏的元凶abc免得它找到自己真正的破坏目标
Is find out what damaged his heart Before it goes after something he really needs.
是什么能把个20岁小伙的心脏破坏至此?
So what damages A healthy 20-year-old heart
使其到处散播凝血 就跟发射导弹似的
Enough to make it send out clots like it's bombing dresden?
- 狂犬病病毒?abc- 会把他的肾也给毁了的
- Rhabdo? - Would have fried his kidneys too.
- 那毒性弥漫性甲状腺肿呢?abc- 甲状腺功能检查正常
- What about graves? - Thyroid function tests were normal.
库兴氏病abc皮质醇的过量产生可能影响心率
Cushing's.Cortisol overproduction could interfere with heart rhythm.
去做个地塞米松抑制试验
Run a dexamethasone suppression test.
Annie
Annie.
你打了我
You hit me.
我知道 我很抱歉 但是...
I know. I'm so sorry,but...
那不是我
It wasn't me.
我知道 如果你能控制自己abc你绝对不会这么做的 但是...
I know you would never have done that If you were in control of yourself,but...
- 但你回来了abc- 是来和你的医生谈谈
- But you came back. - To talk with your doctors.
我不断反思发生的这一切
I've been going over and over what happened,And
不知怎么我突然有了这么一个想法
i had this thought out of nowhere.
自从我认识Scott之后abc我就看到他的左手乱摔东西
Ever since i've known scott,i've seen his left hand throw things
但总像是开玩笑般的 觉得这很好玩
But always sort of playfully,thinking it's fun.
但当他扔这个时...
But when he threw this...
是出于愤怒
It was angry,
当我把这递给他 他扇我的时候也是
And that's when his hand slapped me,too,When I brought it to him.
这是不是代表什么?
Could it mean something?
按说不应该...你多久用一次?
Deodorant shouldn't-- How often do you use it?
呃 一天几次 这是超强效的
Uh,a few times a day. It's special heavy duty stuff.
喷的时候得避着别人
I have to send away for it.
在狭小的浴室内喷洒
Sprayed around a bathroom the size of a shoebox.
我去查产品成分
I'll check the ingredients from the manufacturer.
我会查查任何导致健康问题的相关资料
I'll check for any references associated with health issues.
有人很感激
Somebody's grateful.
我们就让你们...三个独自呆会吧
We'll just leave the... Three of you alone.
为什么这个杯子上没有口红印?
Why is there no lipstick on this cup?
Cuddy喝的时候擦着唇膏
Cuddy was wearing lipstick when she drank from it.
口红留在了我的脸上abc为什么没留在杯子上?
It was on my face. Why isn't it on the cup?
为什么在House王国提出一个
Why is it always reasonable in houseland
感情问题并通过把它转化为
To take an emotional problem
一个细节问题来摆脱它总是合理的?
And sidestep it by turning it into a mechanical problem?
因为在House王国 顺便说一下abc以及宇宙的其他任意地方
Because in houseland-- And the rest of the universe,by the way--
当问题出现 我们便需要答案
When a question presents itself,it calls for an answer.
如果左脑解读现实
If the left brain is the interpreter of reality
讲述你的经历
And the one that tells us the story of who we are,
那你的经历是什么?
Then what is your story?
你是想做拥有答案的人abc还是和Cuddy在一起的人?
Do you wanna be the man with the answers,Or do you wanna be the man with cuddy?
我该怎么做?
What do I do?
惹她生气
You make her angry.
你真觉得现在是嘲笑我的最好时机吗?
You really think that was the best time to mock me?
我和你一样惊讶 但我觉得我是认真的
I'm as surprised as you,but I think i'm serious.
交流是不会自己产生的 除非你...
Communication can't start unless you're--
- 我试着惹她生气了 这样才能...abc- 不 你没有 拜托!
- i've been trying to make her angry for-- - no,you haven't.Come on!
粪便 脱衣舞男?abc这都是些常规的玩意
Poo,strippers?It's routine stuff.
你一直手软
You've been pulling your punches.
你害怕了 你该害怕的
You're scared. You should be.
现在... 去吓坏她
Now... Go terrorize her.
你不想销毁它 对不对?
You don't wanna destroy it,do you?
我说了我会 我会的
I said I was gonna do it. I'll do it.
但是你不想
But you don't want to.
我想和你在一起
I wanna be with you.
- 也许不是百分百情愿 但...abc- 假设这是我们结婚五周年纪念日
- Maybe i'm not comfortable with it-- - let's say it's our fifth anniversary.
你准备好销毁它了吗?
Are you ready to destroy it now?
十周年纪念日 三个孩子
Tenth. Three kids.
他们在墨尔本过暑假 abc还有很讨人厌的口音
They spend their summers in melbourne And have annoying accents.
我们幸福得招人嫉恨
It's disgusting how happy we are.
你准备好了吗?
You ready now?
你不是在留后路
You don't have doubts.
你只是不想失去你爱过的人abc唯一留给你的东西
You just don't wanna kill The only thing left of someone you loved.
别销毁
Don't do it.
我对放弃东西一直有困难
I do have trouble giving things up.
比如说...
For example...
我从没取消我们的结婚计划
I never cancelled any of our wedding plans.
注意了!我有事宣布
Attention! I have an announcement.
当你们整天忙来忙去时abc我希望你们都能注意到
As you go about your day,I would like you to be aware of the fact
我和Lisa Cuddy上床了!
That I slept with lisa cuddy!
这白痴透了!
This is beyond ass-hood!
你可以不在乎你的印象! 但我不行!
You have the luxury of not caring about your image.I do not!
我可以允许很多事发生
I can permit a lot of crap,
但是一个员工大喊着abc和我的风流事 不行!
But an employee shouting about His sexual exploits with me--no!
这完全无法容忍!abc所以恭喜你 House
That is zero tolerance! So congratulations,house.
我生气了
I am angry.
我在想我们是不是该搬到一块住
I was wondering if we should move in together.
你被炒鱿鱼了
You're fired.
我觉得没什么可担心
I wouldn't worry about it.
我觉得她喜欢你
I think she likes you.
如果我被开除了 我想这大概abc也意味着我不用看病人了
If i'm fired,i think that probably means I don't have to see patients.
我就是来让你引起注意的
I'm here as a squeaky wheel.
我知道你们医生都是怎么样的
I know how you doctors are.
你们很忙 你们心烦意乱
You're busy,you get distracted.
- 我的检查报告可能就在你的收件箱里abc- 我不需要你的检查报告
- My lab results could be sitting in your in-box. - I don't need your labs.
- 你这是胃酸逆流abc- 你怎么可以...
- You have acid reflux. - Well,how could you--
酸溅在声带上
acid splashes on the vocal chords.
声带拉紧 发出声响
They tense,make that squawking sound.
这完全不影响健康
It's completely harmless.
我给你开张处方 你给我回家
I'm gonna give you a prescription,And you are gonna go away.
你真是个好医生
You are a great doctor.
- 你为什么要动你的皮带?abc- 我一直都动我的皮带
- Why'd you move your belt? - I always move my belt.
弄得我有点疼
Makes me sore.
- 你没告诉我这事abc- 我86岁了 哪不疼?
- You didn't tell me that. - At 86,what isn't sore?
疼痛没发出怪声那么重要
Soreness is less important than squawking.
是发出的怪声让我的妻子烦心
It's the squawking that was bothering my wife.
那不是啤酒肚 是肿瘤
That's not a potbelly. It's a tumor.
这就是我一直在想胰腺癌的原因
That's why pancreatic cancer was on my mind.
我的大脑试着要告诉我
My brain was trying to tell me.
这听起来不太好
This isn't sounding good.
胰腺癌?
Pancreatic cancer?
这会导致胃酸逆流
It can cause acid reflux.
- 我们该好好检查你的abc- 这么说这不太好
- We should scope you. - So it's not good.
- 在癌症里都不算好的abc- 不 不好
- Even for cancer it's not good. - No,it's not.
除臭剂里有很高比例的丙二醇
The deodorant has a high proportion of propylene glycol.
同样的产品使新加坡的一个孩子abc产生了心脏问题 导致了癫痫
Same stuff made a kid in singapore Develop a heart condition,and--get this--seizures.
我们的病人可能根本abc就不需要一个裂脑手术
Our patient may never have needed split-brain surgery.
我相信一半的他会喜欢这个讽刺的
I'm sure he will half-appreciate the irony.
带他去放射科 扫描胰腺
Take this man to radiology. Pancreatic scan.
呆在他身边
And stay with him.
我叫Eugene schwartz
Eugene schwartz.
不管是什么 快点说
Whatever it is,just say it quickly.
你有没有两支同色的唇膏?
Do you have more than one lipstick in the same shade?
比如说一支防脱落的 另一支不防?
Maybe one that has a sealing agent and one that doesn't?
这怎么可能和任何事有关?
How could that possibly be relevant to anything?
你真的不觉得你....
You really don't think you're just...
对那晚反应过激了吗?
Overreacting to the other night?
很好 我反应过激了
Fine. I am overreacting.
你之前对我说过无数令人讨厌的话
You've said plenty of lousy things to me before.
但是...到达底线是一件好事
But...Reaching the final straw has been a good thing
因为这让我意识到abc我们不仅没有私交
Because it made me realize We not only don't have a personal relationship,
也绝对不可能有
We never could.
你 你是
You--you're--
你是因为我说过的一些话....
You've been overreacting...
而产生这么大的反应?
To something I said?
你侮辱我 我走掉
You insulted me. I walked out.
这种事发生过上百次了
It's nothing that hasn't happened a hundred times before.
- 我辞职abc- 好好
- I quit. - Great.
我保姆7:30下班 所以...
My nanny is off the clock at 7:30,So...
你是要一周假?
You're a week off.
你大可回去给那小混蛋喂奶abc但这不过是你的自我安慰
You can go suckle the little bastard child If it makes you feel good about yourself.
你去死
Screw you.
不不 事情不是这样的
No,no,that-- that's not what happened.
我告诉你我需要你 你 你帮了我
I told you that I needed you. You--you helped me.
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
这么说...这是你自己编纂的经历
So...This is the story You made up about who you are.
故事不错
It's a nice one.
可惜不是真的
Too bad it isn't true.
不 我不太好
No. I'm not okay.
* 这是一天的晚上 *
* It is the evening of the day *
* 我坐着看孩子们玩耍 *
* I sit and watch the children play *
* 我能看到他们的笑脸 *
* smiling faces I can see *
* 但他们并非为我而笑 *
* but not for me *
* 我坐着任眼泪滑过 *
* I sit and watch as tears go by *
* 我的财富买不到一切 *
* it is the evening of the day *
* 我希望听到孩子们的歌声 *
* I sit and watch the children play *
* 但我只能听到*
* doing things I used to do *
* 雨点打在地上的声音 *
* they think are new *
* 我坐着任眼泪滑过 *
* I sit and watch as tears go by *
Mayfield精神病院
Mayfield Psychiatric hospital